My name is Flavin Obiero.
I am currently in Fareham,
Hampshire, south of England,
and I'm a farmer, a butcher and a cook.
We tenanted farm, We've got pigs,
we've got sheep, goats.
We've also got a few chickens for eggs.
We sell all our bodies
directly to the consumer.
So we're coming up to our third year.
So let me go four years
to make this something.
So that pressure is always looming.
And I knew that from the beginning.
We moved to England when I was 15 to join
my dad, who was working here.
I wanted to work with animals,
will be a vet,
and it became clear quite quickly
how much work I needed to do to be a vet.
And I didn't do that work sight.
But after doing a week's work experience
on a farm to gain
practical experience,
I decided to go down that road.
I've always liked the practical side.
It's about me and my 16 year
working in the industry.
I enjoy it.
The highs are very high,
the lows are very low,
and you just got to try and find
a nice medium and cruise on that.
When I first went on a farm
in this country, I was 19.
In Kenya, it's
not a big being in farming
because farming is everywhere.
Like I'd say,
pretty much at least 80, 90% of Kenyans
have a direct link
to a form of food production, whereas here
it used to be like that, but now
it's still be three or four times removed.
So like in agriculture in the UK,
you'll probably count
the number of black people
in the industry actively
on two hands at best,
maybe one foot as well.
So going into it,
I think that was I was naive,
which is probably helped me
because I was quite numb
to a lot of the things that were happening
or things I was hearing,
but it was like going to a new club.
We want everyone to like you and to fit
in, but we would.
Madrid on skin color, obviously
always first people often I say, I'm
a farmer and I love that
because I don't like being put in a box.
I think
as as black
people, we might feel
that it's the in the west
that the countryside is not for us, but
you said that
because if you moved here
from another country, Caribbean or Africa,
you had access to the countryside
wherever you wanted.
So one can have that here.
But because society
thinks moving into cities
is where where the money is, most people
from developing countries are coming to
the west.
You're probably coming from a position of
countryside, living poor,
and you're coming here
with the narrative
that living in the city is progress.
I'm a trustee for a charity that like week
long stay visits on our farms
and then all the kids come from
inner city schools.
And you see some of the kids
when they turn up
at the start of the week,
I don't know when they leave.
It's just like being outside,
being in nature, being around animals,
exchanges, people.
We've all got a right
to exist on this planet.
I don't think that
the lack of people that look like
you should stop
you from going out and living in an area
where
you might enjoy it.
And I think even if you're the first
person that some of these people see,
you're going to make it easier
for the next person.
He's like a chain reaction.
So What I've done with
the little resources we've had so far.
Imagine what we can do with more resources
and more of a name and industry.
So yeah, I've still got still got
plenty in the tank, I'd say.